Guide to the Cynthia Westcott papers, 1922-1983
Westcott, Cynthia papers, 1922-1983
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cynthia Westcott papers, 1922-1983.
4095
Cynthia, Westcott 1898-1983
4.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, periodicals, newspapers, notes, manuscripts, line drawings, scrapbooks, photographs, and appointment books.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Business correspondence with publishing companies, with periodicals and newspapers relating to books and articles written by Westcott, and with nurseries about test roses and other plants; general correspondence; some family correspondence; research notes for books and articles; papers related to the American Rose Foundation and Society; manuscripts of talks given to Garden Clubs of America and other organizations; correspondence with and about the author of SILENT SPRING, Rachel Carson; line drawings used as book illustrations; scrapbooks of newsclippings and articles; photographs; Rose Day guest lists; and appointment books.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cynthia Westcott received her Ph.D. in Plant Pathology from Cornell University in 1932. She lectured for the Garden Clubs of America and other organizations, and she wrote books and newspaper columns, including the 1937 book THE PLANT DOCTOR; THE GARDENERS BUG BOOK; AND PLANT DISEASE HANDBOOK.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Business correspondence with publishing companies, with periodicals and newspapers relating to books and articles written by Westcott, and with nurseries about test roses and other plants; general correspondence; some family correspondence; research notes for books and articles; papers related to the American Rose Foundation and Society; manuscripts of talks given to Garden Clubs of America and other organizations; correspondence with and about the author of SILENT SPRING, Rachel Carson; line drawings used as book illustrations; scrapbooks of newsclippings and articles; photographs; Rose Day guest lists; and appointment books.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Westcott, Cynthia,1898-1983; Carson, Rachel, 1907-1964.; American Rose Foundation.; Garden Clubs of America.
Subjects:
Botany.; Plant diseases.; Gardening.; Plants.; Botanists.; Authors.
Form and Genre Terms:
Drawings.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Papers
  - Cynthia Westcott Christmas Letters, 1945-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - C.W. Personal (miscellaneous), 1945-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C.W. Term Paper, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Westcott Family Correspondence, 1951-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1946, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Undated General Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tributes to C.W., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alampi, Phil and Ruth W. Correspondence, 1953-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jenkins, Anna E. Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Johnson, Eileen and Ena Lewcock Correspondence, 1934-1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Rogick, Mary Dora Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Van Slogteren, D.H.M. Correspondence, 1946-1958 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Viehmeyer, Glenn Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Whetzel, Herbert H. Correspondence, 1929-1942 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Azaleas, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Azaleas, 1944-1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Azaleas, 1944-1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Camellias, 1945-1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Roses, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Roses, 1943-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Rose Day, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Rose Research, 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Rose Mildew, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Roses, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Roses: USDA Fragrance and Breeding, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Armstrong Nurseries, 1947-1959 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Armstrong Nurseries, 1960-1977 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Conrad-Pyle Company, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Jackson and Perkins Company, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Jackson and Perkins Compan, 1960-1976 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Other Nurseries, 1956-1977 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - The American Home, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Flower and Garden, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Flower Grower, 191950, 1960, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - New York Times Correspondence, 1956-1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - New York Times Articles, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - New York Times Articles, 1965-1976 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "OPEN" (Ornamental Plants Entomologists Newsletter), 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Articles and Talks, 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, 1950-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Montclair Garden Center, 1952-1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Springdale Garden Club, 1964-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Garden Clubs Talks and Miscellaneous, 1951-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biological Control, 1952-1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Biological Control, 1959-1960, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pests, Pesticides, Biological Control, 1961-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pesticides, Silent Spring, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pesticides, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Equipment Companies, 1933-1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Geigy Agricultural Chemicals, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Plant Disease, Pesticides, 1958-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Plant Disease, Pesticides, 1959-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Entymology Research, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - All-American Rose Selections, Inc., 1959-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American Rose Foundation Research Projects, c. 1960-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - ARF Research, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - ARF Research Committee Reports, 1954-1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - ARF Research, 1952-1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - ARF Research, 1958-1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - American Rose Society, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - ARS, 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - ARF, 1967-1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - ARF Research, Minnesota, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - ARF, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - ARF Research Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - ARF - Wills, Dr. Gamble, etc., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bug Book Letters, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bool Letters, 1950-1958 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Rose Book Letters, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Bug Book Research, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bug Book Names, 1954-1964 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Massachusettes Experiment Station, re: book, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Are You the Garden's Worst Pest?, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bug Book, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bug Book, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1971-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Grolier, Inc., 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Grolier, Inc., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - J.B. Lippincott Company, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - J.B. Lippincott Company, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - J.B. Lippincott Company, 1951-1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Frederick A. Stokes Company, 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1940-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1971-1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Book Royalties, 1962-1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Book Illustrations (line drawings), 1953, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Book Illustrations (line drawings), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Book Illustrations (line drawings), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Book Illustrations (line drawings), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Scrapbooks: Westcott Columns and Articles, 1937, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Scrapbooks: Westcott Columns and Articles, 1937, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Illustrations (Box 4)
  - Photographs (Box 5)
  - Diaries; Rose Day Guest Lists ( 1950, 1953, 1958 ); Notes on Rose Gardens and Tests; scrapbooks (mostly clippings); News Clippings, 1934-1959 (Box 6)